原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
快点  这个破烂
Come on. Piece of shit.
信号总是中断
Signal keeps getting dropped.
我讨厌半夜深入沼泽
I hate being this far in at night.
如果被抓到用这东西捕鱼  我也会紧张的
I'd be sweating too if the law caught me fishing with this.
有了  有了
Oh. I got it. Got it.
看来最后一个投放区在...
Looks like the last drop zone is...
这些树后面
Just beyond these trees.
停下
Hey, hey, stop.
我们到了  伙计们
I think we're here, boys.
你确定吗  埃迪
Sure about this, Eddie?
他说拿三个箱子过来扔在这里
Man said bring out three boxes and drop 'em,
我只知道这个
that's all I know.
那好
All right.
刚刚怎么回事
What just happened?
发动不了
It won't start.
发动不了是什么意思
What the hell you mean it won't start?
发动不了
It won't start.
只是一条鳄鱼  对吧
That... that was just a gator, right?
靠
Shit!
狗娘养的
Son of a bitch!
那是什么鬼东西
What the fuck is that?
他去哪了
Where'd he go?
-过来  -我拉你  快游
- Come on! - I got you. Just swim.
-救命  不要啊  救命  -快点
- Please! Please! Please! - Come on!
快游过来  游过来
Just swim to me. Swim to me.
快点  伙计
Come on, man!
快过来
Just come here!
游过来  伙计
Swim to me, man!
-靠  -他去哪了
- Shit! - Where'd he go?
布莱恩
Blaine!
听  听
Listen. Listen.
怎么了
What?
听  听
Listen. Listen.
靠
Oh, shit!
靠  靠  靠
Shit! Shit! Shit!
靠
Shit!
翻译  布塔
翻译  DustD
翻译  DerbyNinja
翻译  一只茶茶
翻译  马丁马丁回音山
翻译  Sylvia17
翻译  HuskyDawg
翻译  管家大愚
翻译  Sakura的小书包
翻译  余欢
翻译  屯栗子
时间轴  西·查
时间轴  紫夏
校对  布塔
校对  屯栗子
后期  渔夫
字幕总监制  布塔
沼泽   怪物
第一季  第一集
谁被困在城堡里
Who was trapped in the castle?
-凯西公主  -凯西公主
- Princess Cassie. - Princess Cassie.
谁在生她的气
And who was angry with her?
48小时后
巨人国王
The Giant King.
大家说说  为什么巨人国王会生气
Now, why was The Giant King angry, guys?
他们偷走了他所有的金子
They stole all his gold.
因为他们偷走了他所有的金子
Because they stole all of his gold.
但是凯西公主一个人被关在那里
But Princess Cassie was in there by herself.
你们觉得她开心吗
So, do you think she was happy?
-不  -兴奋吗
- No. - Excited?
不
No.
-她有什么感觉  -害怕
- How did she feel? - Afraid.
她害怕  她非常害怕
She's scared... She's very scared.
害怕的时候  应该怎么做
When you're scared, what are you supposed to do?
天啊  苏西  苏西
Oh, my God. Susie! Susie!
刚果民主共和国
把那个放下
Hey, put that down!
住手  把它放下
Stop! Put it down!
住手  住手
Hey... Stop! Stop!
听着  我是想帮你们
Hey, now. I'm trying to help you.
把它放下  放下
Put it down! Put it down.
医生  不要
Doctor, hey, don't!
不要摘下面具
Don't take your mask off!
别害怕
你这样保护妹妹很勇敢
我们也想帮助她
她病得很重
你能帮我吗
我需要你的帮助
你要为她坚强
我不想离开她
你不需要离开她
你也要一起来
我们都一起去
谢谢你
Merci.
好  开始吧  说出来
Okay. Go ahead. Say it.
什么  说你很棒吗
What, that you were great?
说你是英雄吗
That you're a hero?
我还以为你一定会批判我
I thought for sure you were gonna tear into me
冒着感染出血热的风险帮助那女孩
for risking hemorrhagic fever for that girl.
那救了她的命
It saved her life.
再说  我知道你之后会自我批判
Plus, I know you're gonna beat yourself up over that later
所以省省吧
so just please...
我会做所有的检查  别担心
I'll go through all the tests. Don't worry.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我们把剩下的抗生素和检查设备
And we dropped the last of the antibiotics and the test kits
留在了村子里  以防情况再次恶化
in the village in case the water goes south again.
没有你我可怎么办  哈伦
What would I do without you, Harlan?
-给咱俩找男友去呀  -不要
- Work on finding us boyfriends? - No.
好吧  如果你不准备忙那事
Okay. Well, if you're not gonna do that...
之前接到亚特兰大来的电话
Atlanta called earlier.
国内疑似有潜在疫情
There's a possible situation brewing back in the States.
在哪儿
Where?
没开玩笑吧
You're kidding.
路易斯安那州  玛雷
[Marais在法语中有沼泽的意思]
起码不是刚果了
Well, it's not the Congo.
前面左拐
You want to make a left there.
你还记得
You still remember.
你离开家有多久了
How long has it been since you were home?
挺久的
A while.
有人忘了告诉美丽的玛雷
Well, somebody forgot to tell beautiful Marais
1962年是很久以前了
that 1962 was a long time ago.
疾控中心派人来真是太好了
I'm glad the CDC is here
因为我已经黔驴技穷了
'cause I'm running out of options.
现在还是只有三位感染者吗
So, it's still just the three infected?
今天早上来了第四位
Fourth came in this morning.
一个小女孩先出现的症状
Little girl presented first.
她与她的老师和学校护士有过直接接触
She had direct contact with her teacher and the school nurse.
-今天来的病人呢  -一个店员
- And today's patient? - A clerk.
吉德里街上的桑德兰一站店的店员
From the Sunderland One Stop on Guidry.
该死  传播开了
Shit. It's spreading.
是啊
Yeah.
全员都在吗
They all here?
是的
Yeah.
好了  各位
Okay, everyone.
以防有人不知道
For those of you who don't know
我是艾比·亚凯恩医生
my name is Dr. Abby Arcane
是疾控中心流行病情报部门的
with the CDC's Epidemic Intelligence Service.
这部门是真实存在的
That is a real thing.
我的团队来此是为了帮助你们照顾病人
My team is here to assist in caring for your patients
并找出这种疾病的根源
and to find the source of this disease.
我们需要新鲜的血液样本
We need fresh blood samples
还有病人在出现症状之前的
and diaries of each patient's contacts
接触情况记录
before presenting symptoms.
如果我们能鉴别这种疾病
If we can identify the disease,
就能找出治疗方法
we can figure out how to treat it.
不过目前  与病人直接接触的人
For now though, it is masks, gloves and goggles
必须戴上口罩  手套和护目镜
for anyone in direct contact with the patients.
医护人员在我的管理下不能感染  好吗
Caregivers do not get sick on my watch, okay?
我们开始吧
Let's get to it.
亲爱的
Hey, sweetie.
你感觉如何
How you feelin'?
我在她的枕头上发现了这个
So I found this on her pillow.
也许是从救护车上带进来的
Maybe transfer from the ambulance?
我不这么认为
I don't think so.
她入院后一直这样呼吸吗
Has she been breathing like this since she was admitted?
我们通过X光确实在她的肺部发现了
Our X-rays did find a stubborn mycosis
顽固的真菌病  但不是真菌感染
in her lungs, but it's not fungal.
我去让医务人员检查它有没有被污染
I'll have the staff check for contamination.
不好意思
Excuse me?
-你不能拿走那些  -我没有
- You can't take those. - I'm not.
-你没有干什么  -拿走它们
- You're not what? - Taking them.
我只是作为相关方查看报告而已
I'm just looking as an interested party.
这些血检报告是最新的吗
Are these blood tests, are they the most recent?
好吧
Okay.
如果你能给我她入院时的检查报告
If you can give me the tests from when she first came in
我就可以把它们和最新的结果进行比较
I can compare them with the latest results.
你到底是谁
Who are you exactly?
我告诉过你了  这里是禁区
I told you before, this area is off limits.
-操  又来了  -抱歉  亚凯恩医生
- Fuck, again. - I'm sorry, Dr. Arcane.
听着  你在疾控中心的标准规则手册中
Listen, you're not gonna find anything you need
不会找到任何你需要的东西
in the standard CDC rule book.
-我保证  -你说什么
- I promise. - Excuse me.
-叫保安过来  -别别别  没事
- Get security! - No, no, no. It's fine.
-没事  没事  -走吧
- It's fine. It's fine. - Let's go.
我出去了  我走了  我出去了
I'm out. I'm gone. I'm out.
你迟早会有话想问我的
You're gonna wanna speak to me sooner or later.
我们就不能做朋友吗
Hey, can we just be friends?
明天见  鲍伯
See you tomorrow, Bob.
那人是谁
Who the hell was that?
不知道  但我们应该查清楚
No idea. We should find out though.
-苏西的父母有什么消息吗  -妈妈死了
- Where are we on Susie's parents? - Mother's dead.
爸爸埃迪目前下落不明
Her father Eddie's MIA.
警察说他的船不在码头
Cops say his boat's not in his slip
所以他可能在沼泽里
so he could be out in the water.
校车照常接她去上学了
And the school bus picked her up as usual.
所以也许爸爸回家了
So maybe Dad made it home.
治安官
马特
Matt?
调度说有位亚凯恩医生请求支援
Dispatch said a Dr. Arcane requested assistance.
我说绝对不可能
I said that was fucking impossible.
-你现在是警察了  -嗯  四年了
- You're a cop now. - Yeah, four years.
老天  艾比  我没想到还能再见到你
Jesus Christ, Abby. Didn't think we'd ever see you again.
我希望是在更好的情况下重逢
I wish it was under better circumstances.
是啊
Yeah.
-科尔家的女儿  她怎么样了  -不太好
- The Coyle girl. How's she doing? - Not good.
现在她是零号病人
And right now, she's patient zero.
你对她爸爸了解多少
What do you know about her dad?
-谁  埃迪吗  -嗯
- Who, Eddie? - Yeah.
他大部分时间是个渔夫
He's a fisherman, mostly.
抓到他几次违规捕猎  一次酒驾
Pulled him in a few times for game violations, a DUI...
儿童服务中心呢
Child Services?
从没收到过投诉
Never had any complaints.
在这里  这样就算是年度好父亲了
Well, around here, that makes you Father of the Year.
小女孩病倒后我们打了电话  但没人接
When the little girl got sick, we called, but no answer.
鉴于埃迪的船还没回来
And since Eddie's boat was still out
我们就没有想太多
we didn't think anything of it.
科尔先生
Mr. Coyle?
科尔
Coyle!
-马特  -我也听到了
- Matt? - Yeah, I hear it.
科尔先生
Mr. Coyle?
天啊
Oh, my God.
科尔先生
Mr. Coyle?
科尔
Coyle!
-操  -放下  快点
- Fuck! - Drop it, right now!
-什么  -我说放下
- What? - I said drop it!
等等  别开枪
Wait, hold up...
-放下  -我在采集样本
- Drop it! - I'm collecting a sample!
我在采集样本
I'm collecting a sample!
你到底在这儿干什么
What the hell are you doing here?
-你认识这人  -嗯  他之前在医院
- You know this guy? - Yeah. He was at the hospital earlier
-非法闯入  -伙计们
- trespassing. - Guys. Guys!
你们的关注点错了
You're focusing on the wrong thing here.
什么鬼
What the fuck?
他叫亚历克·霍兰
His name's Alec Holland.
过去几个月经常看到他在这一带出没
Seen him around the past few months.
他大概是某种科学家吧
Some kind of, I don't know, scientist-type.
-真的假的  -什么
- Seriously? - What?
你不会逮捕他  对吧
You're not arresting him, are you?
他的确私闯民宅了
He did break in.
不过埃迪·科尔的事与他无关
Well, what happened with Eddie Coyle wasn't because of him.
那是什么鬼东西干的
So what the hell did this?
我来就是想查清楚
It's what I intend to find out.
够了  别问了
That's enough. No more.
不好意思
Excuse me, uh...
亚凯恩医生  我能否和你  再谈一次
Dr. Arcane, can I talk to you for... Again?
-你怎么回事  -怎么了
- What is up with you? - What?
-你明显不是当地人  -对  我
- You're clearly not a local. - No, I, uh...
我只是想帮忙
I'm just trying to help.
去所有你不该去的地方帮忙吗
By being everywhere you shouldn't be?
听我说  你也看到那具尸体了
Listen, um, you saw the body.
你跟这样的东西打过交道吗
Dealt with anything like that before?
我们已经控制住局面了  没事的
We have it under control. It's okay.
但是什么都不管用  不是吗
Well, nothing's working, is it?
吡嗪酰胺  乙胺丁醇
Pyrazinamide? Ethambutol?
两者皆为结核药物
你是谁来着
Who are you again?
霍兰  荷兰那个词
Holland, like, the country.
听我说  听我说
Listen. Listen, listen, listen.
埃弗里·桑德兰雇我采集分析生物...
Avery Sunderland hired me to collect and analyze biological--
恭喜啊  他是这地方的大人物
Congratulations. He's a very important man around here.
谢谢你了  重点在于
Thank you very much. The thing is
我发现了一些疯狂的东西
is that I've been finding some serious fucking crazy.
-疯狂  -对  指的是
- Crazy? - Yes, as in
我以前从未见过的生物进程
biological processes I've never seen before
我认为它们可能与你病人的感染有关
and I think that they could be connected to your infection.
怎么说
How?
直接展示给你比解释要简单
It's easier to show you than to tell you.
桑德兰的实验室在沼泽里  二十分钟就能到
Sunderland's lab's on the water, 20 minutes out.
-有病人在等我  -当然
- I have patients waiting. - Yes. Yes.
我知道他们在等  他们在等的是治疗方法
I know they're waiting. They're waiting for a cure,
但我猜医生们
but I'm guessing the doctors
还没查出病原体是什么
haven't had any luck ID'ing the pathogen yet.
没错
No.
你喜欢悬疑故事吗
You like mysteries?
老故事  比如
You know, old mystery,
《女作家与谋杀案》  《神探科伦波》
like Murder She Wrote, Columbo...
-怎么了  -什么
- What? - What?
我喜欢那些不是80年代的梗
I like references that aren't from the 1980s...
我一下就想到...不非得是...
It was the first thing that popped in my... It doesn't have to--
-不  我对悬疑故事不感兴趣  -好吧
- Well, no. I don't like mysteries... - Okay.
-我想要解决方案  -我也是
- I like solutions. - Me, too.
所以让我来帮你找出解决方案  好吗
So let me help you find one, okay?
好吗  回到医院
Okay? Going back to the hospital,
转来转去  想找出答案
spinning around, trying to find an answer...
这样做不会让你更接近真相
It's not gonna get you any closer to the truth.
但是去那里
But going out there
就会找到答案
that will.
-好吧  -好的
- Okay. - Okay.
说动了  说动了  我们走
That worked, yeah. That worked. Here we go.
你怎么知道我不是本地人
How'd you know I wasn't a local?
你穿着名牌人字拖
You're wearing designer flip-flops.
不过很舒服
Comfy suckers, though.
还有你的态度
And the attitude.
也暴露了你
It's a bit of a giveaway, too.
小心脚下
Watch your step.
有点窄
It's tight.
他在哪儿
Where is he?
你干什么去了
What were you doing?
干什么去了  快过来
What were you doing? Come on.
有点陡  小心
It's a little steep, be careful.
这是我的伙伴  狼人
This is my, uh, buddy, Garou.
这是什么研究
What kind of study is this?
我这种垃圾生物学家梦寐以求的研究
It's the kind dip-shit biologists like me dream about.
看看这个
Check this out.
好了
All right, um...
你对诱变剂了解多少
How much do you know about mutagens?
能导致癌症  摧残人类DNA的东西
The stuff that causes cancer, that blows holes in human DNA...
对  那是我们已知的诱变剂
Right. The ones we know about.
对吧
Right?
我就快在这片沼泽深处
I'm close to identifying an entirely new strand
找到一种新型诱变剂了
buried deep in this swamp.
好  是这样的
All right, here we go.
在过去的七个月里
So, um, for the last seven months
我一直在沼泽里
I've been out on the water
在地图上标记
mapping out biological hotspots
诱变活性最强的生物热点
where the mutagenic activity is the strongest
问题是  过去两周
and the thing is, is that for the last two weeks
我注意到这些生物进程的速度在稳步增长
I've noticed a steady increase in speed of these processes.
然后这个
And this...
是我昨天在一个最活跃的位置
is a sample I took just yesterday, um
采集的样本
at one of the most active sites.
上面这层透明的  只是沼泽水  对吧
This clear shit on top, that's just swamp water, right?
但是底部这些  看到了吗
But right there on the bottom, you see that?
看到了
I do.
这些不应该出现
That doesn't belong.
松萝铁兰
Green Spanish moss.
植物培养基
Plant-based growth medium.
我学过这些
I've taken a few classes.
准备好了吗
You ready?
天啊
Oh, my God.
霍兰
Holland!
操  停下来
Fuck! Stop!
-刚刚怎么回事  -操
- What just happened? - Fuck.
我不知道
I don't know, um...
我认为试管底部的物质  我不...
I think the stuff at the bottom of the tube, I don't... I...
肯定是某种生物促进剂之类的东西
It's gotta be some sort of biological accelerant or something.
-就像是肥料  -对
- Like a fertilizer. - Yeah.
但是它只会增强诱变剂
But it only jacks up mutagens.
怎么了
What?
你想检查苏西·科尔两天前
You wanted to test Susie Coyle's blood from two days ago
和今天的血液  对比是否有改变
against today's to see if it had changed.
对
Yes.
这可能真的是让人生病的罪魁祸首
This really could be what's making people sick.
就像《神探科伦波》一样
It's like Columbo.
好了  可以给科尔的尸体做尸检了
All right, Coyle's body is ready for postmortem.
拜托告诉我
Tell me, please, that you
你把这些科幻情节都备份好了
have all this science fiction backed up.
-都存在硬盘里了  -好
- A hard-drive away. - Okay.
-你能送我去医院吗  -好
- Can you get me to the hospital? - Okay.
他们可能不让我进去  不过
Might not let me in, but...
玛雷市政厅
各位
People.
社区中心
今晚召开紧急会议
静一静  各位  静一静
Settle down, people. Settle down.
我知道这个病弄得大家都心神不宁
I know this bug has got everyone rattled,
但医生们正竭尽全力
but the doctors are doing everything they can.
大木材公司来这里
Big timber's coming in,
倾倒垃圾  焚烧树木
dumping their trash, burning trees...
这片沼泽养活了我们
The swamp puts food on our tables.
我们失去它  就失去了一切
We lose that, we lose everything!
快承认吧  莱利
Just say it, Riley!
沼泽受够了  这就是报应
The swamp's had enough. This is payback.
对
Yeah!
我们还不确定这到底是什么情况
We... We don't know what this is yet.
医院在不眠不休地调查  还有疾控中心
The hospital is on it 24/7, and the CDC.
扯淡
Bullshit.
等一下  等一下
Hold on! Hold on!
我不是说你们错了
I'm not saying you're wrong,
但现在先让医生做他们的工作
but right now, let the doctors do their work.
去你的  埃弗里  我可没钱看医生
Hell, Avery, I don't got money for doctors.
如果严重到那份上  你就来找我
It comes to that, you see me.
你们所有人都可以来
Goes for all of you.
你们知道的
You know that.
也许你应该
Maybe you ought to put
把桑德兰家族的钱拨给这个镇
some of that Sunderland money into this town
而不是浪费在你那个破实验室里
and less in that nonsense lab of yours.
你们知道  这片沼泽在我小时候
You know, the swamp took my father from me
就夺走了我的父亲  你们知道吧
when I was still a boy. You know that, right?
但自那以后  也是这同一片沼泽
But ever since, that same swamp
给我和你们  给这整个镇
has given me, you, and this whole damn town
提供了生计
a way of life.
没错  这个地方有特别之处
Yeah, there's something special about this place
我们都心知肚明
you know that, we all know that.
你们在这里生活得够久了  足以从骨子里
And you live here long enough, you feel it
感受到其特别之处
in your bones.
我现在的研究
Now, my research
是关于未来的
is about the future
将揭示沼泽还能为我们提供什么
uncovering what else the swamp can offer.
新型药物和肥料  天知道还有什么
New medicines, fertilizers, God knows what else.
而如果我们的发现正如我希望的那样
And if what we find is worth what I hope it is
那它可能就是这个镇子问题的解决办法
that could be the answer to this town's troubles.
更像是你自己的问题吧
Your troubles, more like it.
水涨船高  利昂
A rising tide lifts all boats, Leon,
你那台破船也一样
even that shitbox of yours.
没错  我们都遭受了损失
Hell, yeah, I took a hit and we all did.
是啊
Yeah.
我本可以选择离开这里
I could have pulled up stakes
让玛雷陷入困境
and left Marais high and dry.
但玛雷是我的家乡
But Marais is home.
我的爸爸埋葬于此
Where my daddy is buried.
还有我的女儿
And my little girl.
我在这里遇见了玛丽亚
Where I met Maria.
现在  如果我和你们大部分人一样
Now, if I was like most of you
年轻二十岁  我会回去继续工作
and 20 years younger, I'd get my ass back to work.
好了  大家听好了
All right, folks, listen.
我们会及时告知最新进展  谢谢
We'll, uh, post updates as we get 'em. Thank you.
借过一下
Excuse me.
当然
Of course.
你刚才说得真好
That was a nice speech.
你在这里做什么  霍兰
What are you doing here, Holland?
你收到了吗
Did you get 'em?
你收到我昨晚发给你的结果了吗
Did you get the findings I sent you last night?
收到了  我还奇怪是为什么
I did, and I was wondering why
因为我两周前就解雇你了
since I dismissed you two weeks ago.
是这样吗
Is that what that was?
好吧  事情变得越来越有趣了
Well, I assumed you'd reconsider
我还以为你会重新考虑一下
since things were just getting interesting.
说出你的来意吧
Say what you came to say.
在过去两周里  诱变剂的进化周期
For the last two weeks, the evolutionary cycle of the mutagen
持续飙升
has just continued to skyrocket
而现在莫名其妙地人们开始生病
and now out of nowhere, people are just getting sick?
你认为这两件事之间有联系
And you think there's a connection?
对  不能排除这种可能  是的
Yeah, I mean, yeah. I mean, I can't rule it out. Yes.
你不必这么火急火燎的  霍兰
You don't need to set your hair on fire either, Holland.
我不是科学家
I'm not a scientist,
但疾病在玛雷并不罕见
but disease is not uncommon around Marais.
1986年爆发过一次疫情
We had an epidemic in '86,
1992年又有一次
and one in '92.
人会生病  没什么不正常的
People get sick. They always have.
是啊  有道理
Yeah, sure. That makes sense.
-但我没能说服你  -是的  埃弗里
- But you're not convinced. - No, I'm not, Avery.
你雇我来进行科学研究  我现在有所发现
You, uh... You hired me to follow the science and here I am.
我雇的还是个想重新开始的人
I also hired a man looking for a second chance.
这个镇子不需要恐慌
This town doesn't need a panic.
也不需要疫情  埃弗里
It doesn't need an epidemic either, Avery.
亲爱的  亚当斯先生想和你谈谈
Honey, Mr. Adams would like a word.
天哪  好
Oh, boy. Aye-aye!
回家吧  霍兰  交给我们
Go home, Holland. We got it from here.
好
Okay.
好吧
你不睡觉的吗  亚凯恩博士
Do you ever sleep, Dr. Arcane?
其他人睡的时候我就不睡
Not when everyone else does.
叫我艾比
And it's Abby.
你有看过尸检吗
Have you ever seen an autopsy?
有
Yeah, yeah.
看过一次外星人尸检
Saw an alien autopsy once.
很肯定那是假的
Pretty sure it was fake though.
好吧
All right.
我要去准备好测试装置
I'm, uh, gonna set up the test gear.
你们玩得开心
You kids have fun.
那个女孩怎么样
How's the girl?
药物治疗减缓了成年病人的病情恶化
The drug therapy is slowing the beast in the adults,
但是
but...
苏西入院时  已经感染了两天  所以
Susie had gone for two days before we got to her, so...
而且她才九岁
She's also only nine years old.
这不是你的错
It's not your fault.
直接从身上取出的植物样本  你请自便
A plant sample, straight from the source. Knock yourself out.
谢谢
Thank you.
有反应
Got a reaction here.
我们得走了
We gotta go. We gotta go.
快点  快点  快点
Come on. Come on. Come on. Come on.
天啊
Oh, my God!
亚历克
Alec!
操
Fuck!
快走  快走  快走
Come on! Come on! Come on!
苏西
Susie.
爸爸
Daddy!
艾比  艾比  等等
Abby! Abby, wait!
快去  快
Go, go, go, go!
苏西  苏西
Susie. Susie.
让开  让开  让开
Clear! Clear! Clear!
她需要抢救
She's Code Blue.
醒醒  亲爱的
Come on, honey.
醒醒
Come on.
苏西
Susie.
心跳恢复了  重新输液
Okay, I'm getting something. Restart the IV.
你还好吗
You all right?
你头发上有...
You have a, uh...
是一块玻璃
It's a piece of glass.
现在怎么办
So what now?
我们不能就这么坐着
We can't just sit here.
我要去查点东西
I'm gonna go check something out.
你来吗
You coming?
有波本威士忌喝吗
Does it involve bourbon?
还真有
Actually, yes.
什么
What?
我说喝波本威士忌是开玩笑的
I was just kidding about the, uh, bourbon.
我的一个朋友在里面  她是记者
A friend of mine's inside. She's a reporter.
她也许知道埃迪为什么去沼泽
Maybe she knows why Eddie was out in that water.
戴尔瑞餐馆
这就是你经常来的地方吗
This is where you used to hang out, huh?
这是玛雷人经常来的地方
This is where everybody in Marais hangs out.
你正前方有个可怕的女人
Scary woman, 12 o'clock.
仙都
Xanadu.
不敢相信她还在这里
Can't believe she's still here.
艾比·亚凯恩
Abby Arcane.
我去
Goddamn!
我听说你回城了
I heard you were back in town.
莉兹
Liz.
戴尔瑞去备货了  但我知道他会想见见你的
Delroy's on a supply run, but I know he'd wanna see you.
我也很想见见你的父亲  但...
Uh, yeah, I'd love to see your dad, but it's, uh...
我们现在不是那种走亲访友式的见面
It's not that kind of visit.
也是
Right.
大概不是疫情爆发
Guess it'd take nothing less than a medical meltdown
你也不会回来玛雷
to bring you back to Marais.
亚历克·霍兰
Uh, Alec Holland,
-这位是莉兹·崔梅恩  -你好
- this is Liz Tremayne. - Hi.
我...
I...
你们先聊着  我去拿喝的
Yeah, you guys catch up, I'll get the drink.
他怎么穿个凉鞋
What's with sandals?
别管他
He's all right.
那么
So...
听说你在埃迪·科尔身上
Heard you found something seriously messed up
发现了些特别糟糕的东西
over at Eddie Coyle's.
听谁说的
Who said that?
外面都在这么传  艾比
It's out there, Abby.
这地方
This town...
你还在《回声》工作  对吧
You still work for the Echo, right?
我需要你帮个忙
I need a favor.
我得先把科尔的报道写出来
I gotta write the Coyle story
才能帮你压住新闻
before I can hold it.
我不是那个意思  只是...
I'm not saying that, I just, um...
你最近有在码头注意到任何不寻常的事情吗
Have you seen anything unusual at the docks lately?
等下  你就是艾比的那个记者朋友
Wait, you're Abby's reporter?
在《玛雷回声周报》工作
For the Marais Echo Weekly.
注意是周报
Emphasis on the weekly.
所以我有时间可以回来帮我爸的忙
So I have time to help out my dad when I can.
-无意冒犯  -有点被冒犯
- No offense. - Some taken.
没多少人愿意开口  艾比
Not a lot of people are talking, Abby.
所以你知道这事有多严重了
So you already know it's bad.
为什么这么说
Why do you say that?
因为这里是玛雷  蚊子和八卦
'Cause it's Marais. Mosquitoes and gossip...
是我们这里的特产
Two things we get a lot of here.
但是...
But...
我听到传闻  有人租用船只
I have heard whispers of someone hiring boats
在晚上进入沼泽深处
to go out into the swamp at night.
谁
Who?
没人知道  是谁或者为什么
No one knows. The who or the why.
-那埃迪·科尔呢  -找不到他的船
- And Eddie Coyle? - His boat was never found.
然后科尔的另一个船员  也不见踪影了
And the guy he crewed with, he's AWOL, too.
大家最后听说的是  他们要去蚊子湾
Last thing anyone heard they were headed out to Skeeter Cove.
该死
Oh, shit.
艾比...
Abby...
不用  坐着就好
No. Sit.
你们能回避下吗
Could you give us a moment, please?
-要喝点什么吗  -不用了  谢谢
- Can I get you anything? - No, thanks.
疾控中心有五千名员工  我查了
Five thousand people work at the CDC. I looked it up.
他们除你之外还有4999种选择
That's 4,999 other options they could have sent.
我工作出色  他们知道我能帮上忙
I'm good at my job. They knew I could help.
我也想帮忙
I wanted to help.
你后来去哪上学了
Where did you end up studying?
埃默里大学
Emory.
好  那我们想一想
Okay. So, let's think about this just for a minute.
你的大一
Your freshman year...
在你出去派对狂欢的时候
When you were going out to parties...
-我没有  -在你出去派对狂欢的时候
- I didn't-- - When you were going out to parties...
你整个大一期间我都在肖娜的卧室里
I spent your freshman year in Shawna's bedroom.
桑德兰夫人...
Mrs. Sunderland...
我每天都会想起肖娜
I think about Shawna every day.
现在轮不到你讲话
I'm speaking now.
大二
Sophomore year...
也许那时候你想明白了
Maybe that's just about the time you figured out
自己的人生目标是什么
what you wanted to do in life
然后选定了专业
and declared a major.
那时候我
That's about the time I...
爬下她的床  开始酗酒
stumbled out of her bed and into a bottle.
很多的酒
A lot of bottles.
我真正想要忘记的
Now, what I'm really trying to forget
是你的大四
is your senior year.
因为在你申请医学院的时候
Because while you were applying to medical schools
我丈夫在跟离婚律师谈
my husband was talking to divorce lawyers.
正是这种失去他的想法
It was the thought of losing him
最终让我戒了酒
that finally made me quit drinking.
我问埃弗里
And I asked Avery
那种力量从何而来
where that kind of strength came from.
他说
And he said
因为
it's because...
所有的黑暗都不是我的错
all that darkness wasn't my fault.
是你的错
It was yours.
你说你很擅长你的工作
You said you're good at what you do
你能帮上忙  所以你才来这里
and that you can help, that's why you came here.
所以我才允许你留下来
And that's why I'm letting you stay.
-但如果那个小女孩死了...  -不会的
- But if that little girl dies-- - She won't.
向我保证
Promise me.
说啊  保证
Go ahead. Promise.
我保证
I promise.
一旦她好转
Within the minute she's better
我要你立刻离开
I want you gone.
我们应该去蚊子湾看看
We... We should go check out Skeeter Cove.
好
Okay.
天哪
Oh, my God.
搞什么
What the hell?
这怎么可能
How is that even possible?
我不知道
I have no idea.
有发现
Found something.
电脑
Laptop.
应该有用
That could help.
拿着这个
Here, hold this.
什么东西
What is it?
这像是
It's like a...
某种水下释放装置
Underwater release mechanism or something.
释放什么
Releasing what?
我不知道
I don't know.
把它带回实验室吧
Let's take it back to the lab.
我们看看你是什么
Let's see what you are.
光是有他就值得回来了
It's almost worth coming back just for him.
你在干什么  烦她吗  过来
What are you doing, buggin' her? Come here.
下楼去
Go downstairs.
-谢谢  -嗯
- Thank you. - Yeah.
现在我们等着
And now, we wait.
桑德兰夫人就是你不常回家的原因吗
So, is, uh, Mrs. Sunderland the reason you don't visit home much?
她会说我才是我不常回家的原因
She'd say I'm the reason I don't come home much.
而且她说得对
And she's right.
你有过这种感觉吗
Do you ever feel like that?
所以我才在这里
That's why I'm here.
我们有一个共同点了
One thing we have in common.
你想喝杯酒吗
May I offer you a drink?
我绝对需要喝一杯
I sure as hell could use one.
我们有两个共同点了
That's two things we have in common.
好
Okay.
看看有什么
Let's see.
-杯子  -别用杯子了
- Glasses... - It's... It's okay.
好
Okay.
给你
Here you go.
我
I...
有件事要坦白
have a confession.
你是《神探科伦波》粉丝站站长
You're the president of the Columbo fan page.
不是  我
No. No, I...
我谷歌搜索你了
I Googled you.
什么时候
When?
今天早些时候
Earlier today.
亚历克·霍兰
前途无量的科学家承认伪造实验结果
名誉扫地的科学家被剥夺经费  奖学金
诱变剂研究是骗人的
嗯  你居然以为我没看过这些  真好笑
Yeah. Yeah, it's funny you think I haven't seen those.
-对不起  -不  没事
- I'm sorry. - No. No. It's fine.
那这是真的
So, it's true?
什么
What?
我为了更好地证明结论篡改数据的事吗
That I, uh, manipulated the data to better prove my conclusion?
是的
Yeah. Yeah.
我依然坚持我的结论
I still stand by what I found.
但你无法重现那些结果
But you couldn't replicate the results.
目前还不能
Not yet.
好吧  那当时为什么要这样做
Okay. So, why do it then?
当时为什么要这样做
Why do it then?
能给我喝一口吗
Yeah, um... Can I have that?
我不知道  不  我知道
I don't know. No, I know.
我一直想通过我的研究出名
I always wanted to be known by my work,
我想让我的研究定义我这个人
you know, I wanted the work to define me and, uh...
现在的确实现了  只不过不是我想要的方式
Well, now it does, just not in the way I wanted.
那你是怎么到这里来的
So, how did all that land you here?
这座宫殿吗
Oh, in this palace?
当尘埃落定  我很快意识到
Well, when the smoke cleared, I realized pretty quickly
我原来追求的东西错了
that I was chasing after the wrong things, you know.
我不
I don't...
需要在知名期刊发表论文
need to be published in the big journals or, uh,
或是出现在高中生物课本上
taught in high school biology classes
尽管那会相当不错  但是
although that would be pretty cool, but...
不
No.
乐趣一直都在发现过程中
The joy's always been in the discovery.
所以
So...
我们犯下的错误大概常会伴我们左右
Guess sometimes the mistakes we make stay with us.
我愿意付出一切  能让你在搜我名字时
What I wouldn't give for you to Google my name,
上面显示
and it'd just say...
"抱歉  查询不到您搜索的信息"
"Sorry, your query got back no results."
看来我们有三个共同点了
Well, look at that it's three things we have in common.
什么  什么意思
What? What do you mean?
提到埃弗里·桑德兰
Speaking of Avery Sunderland...
他和妻子曾有一个女儿
He and his wife had a daughter...
肖娜
Shawna.
我们从小就是最好的朋友
Growing up, we were... We were best friends.
她就像我的姐妹  桑德兰夫妇...
She was like my sister. The Sunderlands were...
他们...
They were, uh...
他们就像我的父母
They were like parents to me.
就在高中毕业前两天
And two days before we graduated,
我
I, um...
好了  去看看结果吧
Right. Let's grab that.
不
No...
抱歉  我是说就在你们毕业前两天
Sorry. I mean, two nights before you graduated...
怎么了
What?
我杀了她
I killed her.
我们去看结果吧
Let's check that result.
-好  -去拿结果吧
- Oh yeah. - Let's get those results.
该死
Shit.
怎么了
What?
箱子里的东西是某种生物促进剂
This stuff in the box, it's a biological accelerant.
跟我们从沼泽里提取到的很像
It's like the stuff we pulled from the swamp.
但是浓度高出
Like, it's times...
很多
a lot.
所以是有人倒在这里的吗
So, someone's dumping it here?
好吧  提取样本让我带回医院
Okay. Pull some samples I can take back to the hospital.
怎么  你觉得这东西有帮助
What, you think that could help?
我是说  如果就是这东西催化病原体
I mean, I think if this is what's turning our pathogen
导致人们生病的话
into what's making people sick,
或许我们有办法减缓感染速度
maybe there's a way we can slow the infection.
苏西和其他病人等不了了
Susie and the others aren't going to wait.
好吧
All right.
所有的样本都在这里了
All the samples are here.
你肯定比我清楚你需要什么
And you'll know what you need better than I do.
所以我就...
So, I'm gonna...
-你要去哪儿  -我们在船上找到的电脑
- Where are you going? - The laptop that we found on the boat
上面有很多GPS定位
this thing is showing these GPS locations
我觉得
and I'm thinking
这些标记的是其它促进剂箱子
that they're markings where other
被扔下的位置
accelerant boxes have been dumped.
所以
So...
我要在更多人生病之前把它们都捞上来
I'm gonna fish 'em out before other people get sick.
好  行  那我们医院见
Good. Good. Yeah. I'll see you at the hospital.
你没事吧
You okay?
嗯
Yeah.
艾比
Abby...
你为什么搜索我
Why'd you Google me?
抱歉  查询不到您搜索的信息
I'm sorry, but your query got back no results.
真行
That was pretty good.
听着  我可能找到了一些
Listen, I think I may have something
能帮助我们控制这种疾病的东西
that could help us get a handle on this disease.
不管是什么我们都用得上
We could use anything you got.
药物治疗方案可以减缓病情恶化
This drug regimen slowed this thing,
但并不能彻底阻止它
but it hasn't stopped it.
你需要我做什么
What do you need from me?
我需要进入医院实验室
I need access to the hospital's lab
花点时间研究一些新的发现
and time to go through some new findings.
没问题  我马上去办
You bet. I'll get on it.
谢谢  哈伦
Thank you, Harlan.
你好
Hello?
需要我帮...
Can I help--
亚历克
Alec!
天哪
Oh, my God.
亚历克
Alec!